Common Experience collection 11.200.CommonExperience
University Archives, Texas State University
- Truth, 2019-2020
  While investigating Truth through University Seminar (US 1100) courses, students will understand how truth operates in the context of a university and how students, faculty, and staff seek truths on a daily basis through courses and research. However, truth is not limited to the academic environment — by interrogating common frameworks of truth from nuanced, multidisciplinary lenses, we're empowering students to navigate post-graduate life with an unparalleled critical thinking skill set. This theme will catalyze a collaboration among students, faculty, staff, and the surrounding community. Together, we will discuss the meaning, nature, embodiment, and action of truth and how all involved can become more involved and empathic global citizens. ...
  All past Common Experience themes have explored truth. However, by focusing solely on the concept, students can look at truth through every lens: a quest for truth, a search for truth, and an examination of authenticity. Areas of exploration will range from an understanding of university truth — in scholarship and research — to a definition of Universal Truth with a capital T, and from one's own personal truth to a sense of honesty, accuracy, validity, and truthfulness.
  - Theme, 2019-2020 (Box 11)
    Information on theme and news releases.
  - What the Eyes Don't See: A story of crisis, resistance, and hope in an American city by Mono Hanna-Attisha, 2019-2020 (Box 11)
- Dynamics, 2020-2021
  Our Common Experience theme for the 2020-2021 academic year is Dynamics. When we discuss dynamics, we're talking about movement. It's motion — but it's more than that. Think of the motivating forces behind everything, everywhere. There are physical forces, moral forces, and driving forces. You can see and feel dynamics in growth, change, inspiration, and action. We will consider the movement from where you are to where you will be, approaching dynamics both literally and metaphorically, from the observations of astrophysics to the momentum of daily life.
  This theme will ask you to explore your own experiences in the contexts of space, place, movement, and time. By studying the past while examining your personal values, you can trace the paths of social, political, and cultural movements. Each new opportunity will add knowledge and experience — leading you to see the influences and responsibilities you have in shaping our global future.
  ---From Common Experience website
  - Theme, 2020 (Box 11)
    Information on theme, news releases.
- Compassion, 2021-2022
  - Theme